杰
Jay.
-杰... -怎么
- Jay... -What?!
-什么事 -你在打鼾
- What's wrong? - You are snoring!
我吗 对不起
Me? Oh, I'm sorry.
看我家小宝贝
Look at her!
拜托 说好了不许斯黛拉上床
Come on! We said no Stella in the bed.
狗狗还小呢
Oh but she's just a little puppy.
她八成是害怕了 偷偷躲进我怀里
She probably get scared and snuck in.
是吗 那为什么曼尼做噩梦的时候
Oh really? How come when Manny have nightmares
你不准他溜上床
you don't let him snuck in bed?
歌洛莉亚 现在才早晨六点
Gloria, it's six o'clock in the morning,
咱能待会再讨论这个问题吗
can we talk about this later?
请正面回答她的问题 杰
Answer the question, Jay.
我去查一查租赁合同
You know, I'm gonna check the lease,
但我很确信我们不能开个冰毒作坊
but I'm pretty sure we're not allowed to have a meth lab.
你真幽默
You are a delight.
那你这是在做什么
So what are you doing?
我觉得你会喜欢的 我要进行"果汁速度减肥法"
I think you're gonna like this. I'm going on a juice fast.
我爱死了
Mmm. Love it.
讨厌死了 面对现实吧
Hate it. Let's face it,
肚大腰圆的小卡原本就容易情绪失控
A well-fed Cam is hardly a model of emotional stability.
一旦断粮 阶段性地往下发展
Now deprive him of food, and stage by stage,
他便缓缓驶入疯狂的境地
it's a slow descent into madness.
阶段一 大清扫
Stage one--the clean sweep.
毒货
Poison.
-毒货啊 -你觉得这周节食合适吗
- Poison. - Do you think that this is the best week to be doing this?
怎么不合适
Why not?
-我们要去我老板家参加慈善晚会 -那又怎样
- Well, we have that charity thing at my boss' house. - Oh, so what,
我想追求健康生活
I'm supposed to put off my quest for wellness
还必须等到咱俩没有应酬吗
until we're no longer socially in demand?
我人见人爱 没应酬是不可能的
That will never happen. I'm too charismatic.
不 别扔饼干
No. No. Not the cookies.
饼干扔立决
Of course the cookies.
你干嘛总希望我减肥失败
Why do you always want me to fail?
阶段二 拿米奇尔撒气
Stage two--attack Mitchell.
一旦他经不住能多益巧克力酱的诱惑
Because when his diet crashes and burns
减肥计划流产
into a giant pile of nutella,
就把错全怪到我身上
I'm the one he's gonna blame.
不 这回可不行
Well, no, not this time.
这样 我决定和你一起减
You know what? I'm gonna do the fast with you.
减肥计划很棒 我们应该一起执行
I think it's a great idea, and we should do it together.
我们齐心协力 夫夫齐心战美食
So we're on the same team, you know, us versus food.
你的心思我一清二楚
I know what you're doing...
我真的很感动
and I really appreciate it.
不 那将对我也有好处
No, it'll-- it'll be good for me.
我最近也重了几磅
I've actually put on a few pounds.
是啊 之前我都不好意思开口说你肥了
Yeah, well, you know, I didn't want to say anything.
尽管各大股指直线下滑
As the stock market plummeted,
勇敢的年轻人仍不畏高空
brave young men took to the skies,
引领我们进入勇敢无畏的黄金年代
ushering in the golden age of the daredevil.
可敬的人类
How awesome are people?
真可敬
So awesome.
去开门吧 伙计 我按暂停了
You wanna get that, buddy? I'll pause it.
-卢克 还好吗 -好啊 米奇尔舅舅
- Hey, Luke. How's it going? I-- - Hey, uncle Mitchell.
我真没时间闲聊 正在看电影呢
I really can't talk. I'm trying to watch a movie.
好吧 我只是把这袋垃圾食品拿过来
Oh, okay, well, I just wanted to drop off this bag of junk food.
继续说
Go on.
小卡和我在实行"果汁速度减肥法"
Uh, Cam and I are on a juice fast,
所以美食放在家里...
so having this stuff in the house--
我懂了 再见
I connected the dots. See ya.
看到那位年轻的钢丝奇人
Seeing that weird, wonderful little man
精彩的寻梦之旅 我不禁在想
pursuing his dream of walking on a tightrope made me think
或许我也该追求自己的梦想
maybe I could pursue my dream...
拿好了 伙计
Here you go, buddy.
我也要走钢丝
of walking on a tightrope.
加油 老爸 你行的 你可以的
Come on, dad! You got this! You can do this!
全神贯注 保持冲劲
Stay focused! Stay hungry!
没事吧 伙计
You okay, buddy?
什么 当然没事
What? Yeah, hell, yeah, no.
就是为我老爹感到自豪
Just proud of my dad!
那袋子里有好多巧克力
There was a lot of chocolate in that bag.
菲尔 亲爱的 该送卢克上学了
Phil, honey, you gotta take Luke to school.
好的
Got it.
好的 刚才4次里有3次没掉下来
Okay, I haven't fallen three out of the last four times.
今天下午 咱要悬空踩了
This afternoon, we go airborne.
孤零零一个人坐在桌前
Sitting all by yourself at the table.
这一幕似曾相识啊
Now where have I seen that again?
对了 每天在学校自助餐厅都看到
Oh, right. Every day in the school cafeteria.
我选择一个人坐的
I do that by choice.
是校友们选择冷落你吧
The school's choice.
你的绰号就是"校选之花"吧
Isn't that your nickname?
海莉 对妹妹友善点
Haley, be nice to your sister.
艾丽克斯 回得好
Alex, good save.
妈妈 签个字
Mom, sign this.
这是什么
What is it?
校方终于准我升入中级数学班了
They finally bumped me up to the harder math class.
高中数学第三期 沃特斯老师教
Third period, Mr. Waters.
什么 不 妈妈 你不能签
What? No, mom, you cannot sign this.
我在那个班上课
This is my class.
你才高一 学高二数学太早了吧
You're a freshman. What are you doing in second-year math?
你都高三了 干嘛还赖在高二数学班里不走
You're a senior. What are you still doing in second year math?
不是赖着不走 姐是重修
Not "Still." "Again."
艾丽克斯 别对姐姐那么刻薄
Alex, be nice to your sister.
海莉 回得不行
Haley, not a good save.
就知道和你同校肯定受打击
I knew it would suck having you at my school.
你估计得忍耐一下
Well, hang in there.
再过几年 留在学校的又是你一人了
A couple more years, you'll have it all to yourself again.
走吧 姑娘们
Come on, girls.
杰 看她干得好事
Jay, look at this.
全毁了
It's ruined.
斯黛拉干的 她啃我的鞋
Stella did this. She chew on my shoe!
那只笨狗欠管教
You have to discipline that stupid dog.
我经常管教她的
I discipline her all the time.
真的吗 怎么管的 赏她吃纸杯蛋糕吗
Oh, really? How? By buying her little cupcakes?
那不算纸杯蛋糕
They're not real cupcakes.
那是狗狗奖励 用纸杯蛋糕形式发放
They're doggy treats in the form of cupcakes.
你该在曼尼误食之前告诉他的
Yeah, you should have told that to Manny before he ate one.
没关系 他现在可是皮光水滑啊
Oh, come on. His coat never looked better.
要是她把你的鞋啃成这样 看你还乐不乐
You wouldn't find it so funny if she was destroying your shoes.
我从不乱扔鞋子 也就不会...
Well, I don't leave my shoes laying around, so...
这么说鞋子挨啃是我自作自受了
So it's my fault that she chooses to chew my shoe?
我没这么说 这可是你自己说的
I didn't say that. You barely said it.
你不能再这么宠着她了
You have to stop coddling her.
我没宠着她
I don't coddle her.
干嘛
What?
她在喝我的洗澡水呢
She tries to drink the water.
可逗了
It's funny.
上课的时候不许看我 也不许给我发短信
You don't look at me in class. You don't text me.
谁会上课的时候发短信啊
Who would text during a class?
你真是个怪胎
What are you?
亲爱的 我知道现在这个情况
Hon, I realize that this situation is not ideal
对你们两个都不理想
for either one of you,
但有时候 逆境出人才嘛
but sometimes we just rise above things. Yes?
打扰一下 你注意到了路缘是黄色的吗
Excuse me. Did you notice the curb here is painted yellow?
没 我没注意
Uh, no, I did not.
奇怪了 这代表"上下车区域"
Wow. It means loading and unloading.
好吧 我就停一小会 让她们下车
Okay, well, I was just dropping off my kids.
我怎么还没看见有人下车呢
And yet I see no kids emerging from the vehicle.
我们在聊天
Well, we were chatting.
不怕惊着您 长官
At the risk of surprising you a third time, officer,
我这么停车已经好几年了
I've been dropping off here for years, and I--
-开走 -没问题
- Move it. - Okay. You betcha.
她有毛病吧
What was her problem?
我教你 你该这么回她...
Oh, you know what you should have said to her--
什么都不说最好 我不回嘴
Nothing. I should have said nothing would be the point.
我们抬头不见低头见
I have to see her every day.
何必把事情搞得那么僵呢
I mean, why make it worse?
我想表达的就是这个意思
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
人生不如意事十有八九
Awkward, unpleasant situation--
逆境成功
rise above.
过得愉快
Have a nice day.
爱你们哟
Love you!
拜拜
Bye-bye!
"我怎么还没看见有人下车呢"
"And yet I see no children emerging from the vehicle."
再啰嗦 赏你一记粉拳看看
How'd you like to see my fist emerging into your face?
我怎么这么暴力
Oh! Now I think of it!
"果汁速度减肥法"的第四天
Day four of the juice fast,
我很饿 但是感觉很好
and I'm hungry, but I'm-- I'm feeling pretty good.
可是小卡 已经
Cam, on the other hand, has gone all...
边缘精神错乱了
"Girl, Interrupted."
继阶段一 食物大清扫
After one, throwing out all of our food,
和阶段二 拿我撒气
and two, blaming me,
他进入了第三阶段 肥皂剧女王
he entered stage three-- soap actress.
真希望我的傻妹妹多为自己想想
I just wish my sister would put herself out there more.
她如此多才多艺
She has so much to offer.
为何男人都如此肤浅
Why are men so superficial?
随之而来的是第四阶段
That was followed by stage four--
间歇性中邪
a rush of epiphanies...
我 不 需 要 食 物
I... Don't... Need... Food.
看啊 到处都是别致的建筑
Look at this. Architecture is everywhere.
西班牙的运动健将层出不穷
Oh. Spaniards make amazing athletes.
接下来是第五阶段 绝望主夫
Into stage five--despair...
爹地 我们藏好了 但是你没来找我们
Daddy, we hided, but you didn't seek.
小卡
Cam?
然后是狂躁状态
Then came rage.
手里拿的啥啊
Hey. Whatcha got there?
好消息是
The good news is,
小卡从来没坚持过这么久
Cam's never made it this far into a diet before, so...
坏消息是 我对下一阶段会怎样一无所知
Downside--I have no idea what the next stage is gonna be.
但是我可以肯定
But I'm pretty sure
他此时的状态不适合参加派对
it's not charming party guest.
小卡 我在考虑
Cam, I-I was thinking,
明晚我独身赴会 接受老板的摧残吧
I'll take the bullet tomorrow night at my boss' house.
你不必去参加的
You don't have to go to the party.
那些人特无聊
They're--they're boring.
还净做傻事 人也多
Silly cause, you know, lots of people.
车位也紧张
Parking...
-小卡 好歹说句话啊 -你为何如此恨我
- Cam, say something. - Why do you hate me?
我不恨你啊
I don't hate you.
那为什么要把我驱逐出你的生活
Then why are you trying to push me out of your life?
因为你看起来 有点
Because you--you seem a little...
精神错乱
unhinged.
知道我在想什么吗
Okay, well, you know what I think?
你应该少操我的心
You should worry a little bit less about me
多操心你自己
and a little bit more about yourself
想想明晚穿什么吧
and what you're gonna wear tomorrow night,
我看到了你选的那套了
because I saw what you have laid out,
要是穿那套拍照 你一定悔不当初
and I don't think you're gonna like the way you look in photos.
我没决定穿那套啊
Well, I hadn't landed on that.
她几乎五秒钟就要举一次手
Her hand's in the air, like, every five seconds,
还主动提醒沃特斯先生布置家庭作业
and she actually reminded Mr. Waters to assign homework.
同学怨声载道 你知道我有多尴尬吗
The class loved that. Do you know how embarrassed I was?
没有我尴尬
Not as embarrassed as I was
她说8是质数 8唉 妈妈
when she said 8 was a prime number. 8, mom.
行了 你们听着
Okay, fine. You know what?
我今天就给学校打电话 把你们课表换掉
I'm gonna call the school today and have your schedules changed,
但是你们要知道 我今天很失望
but I want you to know a little part of me died today, okay?
我还以为你们能明白
I thought the two of you could understand
姐妹同班对你们都有好处
how being in the same class would benefit you both.
艾丽克斯 你可以辅导海莉的功课
Alex, you--you could've tutored Haley.
海莉 你可以教艾丽克斯交往之道
Haley, you could've helped alex with her social skills.
拜托 你们本该成为超级邓菲无敌档
Come on. The two of you could've been two Super Dunphys.
但现在呢 你们像什么样 邓菲反目吵嘴王
And instead, what are you? Two bickering Half-Dunphys,
我真是痴人说梦才对你们抱期望
and I'm the fool that expected more.
停 我不想听 给我上楼去
No, I don't even want to hear it. Just go upstairs. Go.
这唱的是哪一出啊
What was that?
虎妈独家育儿经
That was a master class in parenting.
现在我们的女儿在楼上
Right now our daughters are upstairs
自以为是地做着决定
making a decision they think is their own,
但实际上 都是我巧妙植入的潜意识
But really, it was an idea that was skillfully implanted by me.
成盗梦师啦 克莱尔
Inception, Claire.
玩的就是心跳 我很喜欢
Dangerous game, but I like it.
那是什么
What are those?
走钢丝专用鞋
Wire walkers.
所谓工欲善其事 必先利其器
You want to go to the dance, you gotta wear the shoes.
带上照相机 卢克
Luke, grab your camera.
卢克
Luke.
我没睡着
I wasn't sleeping.
亲爱的 那好像是...
Honey, I-I think those are...
爵士舞鞋
Jazz shoes.
不是 是钢丝鞋
No. Tightrope shoes.
别人搬家大拍卖时买下的 只穿过一次
Got 'em at an estate sale. Only worn once.
那可不适合...
That--that is not a ringing endorsement for...
菲尔 亲爱的
Oh! Phil, honey.
拜托 小心点
Please be ca--careful. Right.
小心别撞门
Watch the door.
你第三题答案多少
Hey, what'd you get for number 3?
如果我直接告诉你答案 你就学不到东西了
You're not going to learn if I just give you answers.
那如果我给你一点回报呢
Well, what if I gave you something in return?
比如什么
Like what?
你在班上可以跟我讲话
You can talk to me in class.
午餐时间 我要和你们人气王坐一桌
I want lunch at the cool table.
那我要所有题的答案
Then I want all the answers.
延续一周午餐同坐
Then I want a week at the table.
-两次测试答案 -一个月
- That'll cost you two pop quizzes. -A month.
-外加期中考试 -成交
-The midterm. -Deal.
老爸 挺有范啊
Looking great, dad.
走出这几步 我就打破了束缚
With these steps, I break the surly bonds...
上帝保佑
Chicken in a basket!
别拍我
Don't look at me.
-老妈 老妈 -怎么了 怎么了
- Mom. Mom. Mom. -What? What? What? What? What?
妈妈 你打电话给学校了吗
Mom. Mom. Did you call the school yet?
还没呢 我正准备打
Uh, not yet, but I was just about to.
哎哟我去
Uh, Bartles & Jaymes!
那就好 仔细考虑之后
Good. Because we are thinking
我们觉得挺想在一个班的
We might want to stay in that class.
真的吗 孩子们 我不确定啊
Really? Oh, girls, I don't know about that.
拜托了 再给个机会吧
Oh, please let us try it.
超级邓菲无敌档
Super Dunphy?
我抓不住了 抓不住了
I can't hold her! I can't hold her!
好吧 就再待一个星期
Well, maybe one more week.
谢谢 妈妈
Thanks, mom.
好像吃过 一碗汤 一份科布色拉
I don't know. Uh, a cup of soup, a cobb salad.
对 里面有培根
Yeah, it had bacon.
小卡 我没时间跟你讲我今天吃了什么
Cam, I don't have all day to describe all my meals to you.
别再咬我的东西了 你个愚蠢的畜生
Stop eating all my things, you stupid animal.
不是 小卡 我不是在说你
No, Cam, not you.
我回头给你电话
I'll call you back.
坏狗狗
Bad doggy!
你想咬东西吗
You want to chew on something?
行 没问题
Okay. Okay. Okay.
看这个
Look at this.
看这美味的鞋子 尽情咬吧
Look at this delicious man shoe. Eat it.
来吧 咬啊 咬啊
Come on. Eat it. Eat it.
很美味的
Mmm! Yummy.
把鞋子吃掉
Eat the shoe.
来嘛 咬这只鞋子
Eat his shoe. Come on. Eat his shoe.
就像这样
Yeah, like this. Look.
真好吃
Delicious.
妈妈
Mom?
松口
Drop it.
我
I--
别说了 抱歉让你看到这一幕
Please. I'm sorry you had to see this.
你好
hello?
邓菲夫人您好 我是校长助理罗丝
Hi, Mrs. Dunphy. This is Rose in the principal's office.
-您方便跟韦勒校长讲话吗 -好的
-Can you hold for principal Weller? -Yes.
你好 克莱尔
Hi, Claire.
你好 约翰 她又犯什么事了
Hi, John. What'd she do this time?
事实上 她们俩都在我这儿
Actually, I've got both of them in here.
她们俩 真的吗
Both of them? Really?
艾丽克斯给海莉抄作业
Alex was letting Haley copy her homework.
被沃特斯老师发现了
Mr. Waters caught them.
真不敢相信
I-I don't believe it.
我会跟她们俩谈谈
I'm about to have a little talk with them,
所以她们会晚一会儿出来
So they'll be out a few minutes late.
约翰 非常抱歉 说句老实话
Um, I'm so sorry, John, and honestly,
我通常不至于如此教导无方 我发誓
I-I really am a better mother than this. I promise.
你以前也这么说过
So you've said.
不是吧
Seriously?
不是吧 你
Seriously? Oh. You...
抱歉打扰一下
Excuse me.
这是什么鬼东西
Hey, um, what the hell is this?
这片区域仅限上下车
This zone is for loading and unloading,
不是用来讲电话的
not for talking on the phone.
我知道 但是我是在跟校长讲电话
Yeah, I know, but I was talking on the phone to the school
孩子们就要出来了 所以
that my kids were about to come out of, so...
你知道这里有时间限制吗
Are you aware this zone has a time limit?
不 我不知道
N-no, I'm not.
知道不 姐现在还真想发泄几句
You know what? I do want to do some unloading.
我了解你这种人
I know your type.
你的生活太糟 觉得自己很渺小
Life has been bad to you. It has made you feel small.
然后有一天 某人给了你一身山寨警察装
And then one day somebody gives you a fake cop outfit,
一个玩具徽章 和一个破领带
A toy badge and a little spongebob tie.
你突然就想报复社会了 对不对
Suddenly it's payback time, right?
我告诉你
Well, I got news for you,
"法律与秩序：特殊停车警"
"Law & order: Special parking unit,"
我没错
Not my fault.
真对不起 爸爸
I'm really sorry, dad.
没关系的
Oh, it's all right.
在学校吐过的又不止你一个人
Everybody throws up at school.
要是我在学校每吐一次能赚五分钱
If I had a nickel for every time I puked at school,
你猜我一共能赚多少
you know how much money I'd have?
三十五分钱
35 cents.
没错 去洗洗干净 我马上打给医生
Exactly. Now go get cleaned up, and I'll call the doctor.
爸 等等 我不用医生
Wait, dad, I don't need a doctor.
-怎么了 -前些天
- What's up? - The other day,
米奇尔舅舅送了一大袋垃圾食品过来
Uncle Mitchell brought over a bag of junk food
以便他和小卡施行快速减"犹"法
So he and Cam could do a jew fast.
-是果汁减"油"吧 -他说的肯定是"减犹"
- Juice fast? - I'm pretty sure he said "Jew".
随便吧 我截获下来 藏了起来 全都吃了
But anyway, I took the bag, and I hid it, and I ate it all.
不是吧老弟
Oh, buddy.
我情难自禁 我意志薄弱 别鄙视我
I couldn't help myself. I'm weak. Don't look at me.
没关系的
It's all right.
没事的 你从中获得了教训
It's okay. Hey, you learned a lesson.
惨痛的教训
A painful lesson.
我们爷俩都是
I guess we both have.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我一直以为自己是个
I always saw myself as a guy
上天入地无所不能的纯爷们
who could soar through the sky, dancing on a wire.
可我连离地六英寸的钢丝都走不过
I can't even get across one 6 inches off the ground.
也许这正是问题所在
Well, maybe that's the problem.
也许 你之所以会摔倒
Maybe you keep falling
是因为你心里觉得摔下来也无大碍
because part of you knows that you can fall.
如果钢丝架得很高很高 你就不会摔了
Maybe if the wire was much, much higher, you wouldn't fall.
卢克 卢克 卢克
Oh, Luke, Luke, Luke.
你是个天才
You are a genius.
来吧 咱们有活儿干了
Come on. We got work to do.
太给力了 我能先吃个甜甜圈吗
Yes! Can I have a doughnut first?
没问题
Yes, you can!
总算出来了 超级邓菲无敌档
Ah, there they are, my super Dunphys.
我们很抱歉 但我们...
We're sorry, but we just--
你没资格解释
You don't get to talk.
你们今天原本可以进步一些的
You had a chance to be better people today.
你 可以学会和人相处
You, to be more well-rounded,
而你 可以做个好学生
And you, to be a better student.
你们本来能给邓菲家增光的
You could have elevated the Dunphy name,
但恰恰相反 你们却给抹了黑
But instead, you chose to tarnish it,
所以 恭喜二位小姐
So, congratulations, ladies,
你们让家族名誉再次跌得无下限
You brought this family to a new low.
妈 你是不是...
Mom, are you--
是的 没错
Yeah. Yeah, I am,
可以的话 希望你帮我解开这个
And I would actually like to get these loosened up, if I might.
-你以后还继续添乱吗 -绝对不会
- Are we gonna have any more trouble? - No, ma'am.
克莱尔 需要我开车送孩子们吗
Oh, Claire, do you need me to drive the girls?
没事儿 珍妮特 没事儿
All good, Janet. All good.
尝尝奶酪团子吧
Goat cheese risotto ball?
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
确定吗 很好吃的哦
Are you sure? They're so good.
闪一边儿去
Walk away.
就算我精力充沛 也很难控制住小卡
It's tough enough to deal with Cam when I'm at full strength.
但我跟他一样经受了"果汁速度减肥法"的摧残
But I have been fasting just as long as he has,
所以我也没力气
and I do not have the energy
去对付那个可怜的"大怪头"
to deal with a big, needy brisketcase--
大侩...大块头
Brass--basketcase.
小卡 别生我的气
Cam! Don't be mad at me,
但你真的得吃点儿东西
But I think that you really need to eat something.
什么
What?
你应该支持我的
You're supposed to be my support.
离我远点儿 你个狐狸精
Oh, away from me, temptress.
以前叫你狐狸精是爱你 现在是真恨你
And I never thought I would call you that in a negative way.
我看她做过很多疯狂的事儿
I've seen her do a lot of crazy stuff,
但此次的疯狂又上升一个等级
But this is a whole new level.
这饼干是给人吃的吗
Is this a people cookie?
吃吧 没事儿
You're good.
你只要说"是"或"不是"就行了
A definitive "yes" or "no" would be appreciated.
上次的蛋糕已经给我留下阴影了
Those cupcakes did a number on me.
你高兴了吧
Are you happy?
你让我自贱到吃鞋子的地步
You have reduced me to a person who eats a shoe.
-歌洛莉亚 坐下 -你觉得很好玩吗
- Gloria, sit. -You think this is funny?
把我当狗一样地使唤
To talk to me like I am a dog?
我可没有把你当狗一样使唤
I'm not talking to you like you're a dog.
我只是请你坐下 好把问题解决了
I'm just asking you to sit so we can get to the bottom of this.
好吧
Okay, fine.
真乖
Good girl.
拜托 你自己给我机会的
Come on. You set me up.
歌洛莉亚 你为何表现的那么疯狂
Gloria, why are you acting so crazy?
不就是条狗嘛
It's just a little dog.
不是狗把我逼疯了
It's not the little dog that is making me crazy.
是你把我逼疯了
It's you that is making me crazy.
-我 -没错 你以前把我放在第一位的
- Me? -Yeah, you used to put me first.
以前是我陪你洗澡
You used to want me in that shower.
我是不是该"非礼勿听"
Should I be here for this?
不用 曼尼 没关系 我走 但我要告诉你
No, Manny. It's okay. I go. But I want you to know this.
在我老家 男人都宠着女人
Where I come from, men cherish woman.
老婆第一 情人第二 狗第三
It goes wife, mistress, dog.
狗永远排在最后
Dog always at the bottom.
大伙都知道 我经常被邀请
As you can imagine, I get asked to help,
去帮忙解决些环境问题
Uh, with a lot of these environmental causes.
通常 我只是买张票
Usually, I buy a ticket,
买双奥尼尔的战靴
Uh, bid on Shaquille O'Neal's big shoe...
完事儿就回家了
and, uh, come home.
但后来发生了件事儿
But then, something happened.
我爱好腹板冲浪
I love paddle surfing.
每次出海 我都能碰到一头海狮
And each time I'd go out, I'd see this one sea lion.
它抬起头 看着我玩
He'd pop his head up. He'd check me out.
我都习以为常了 甚至给它起了个名字 斯诺克斯
I got so used to seeing him, I even named him--Snorkels.
天呐 我不喜欢故事的发展路线
Oh, god, I do not like where this is going.
有一天 我出海碰到了斯诺克斯
So one day, I, uh, I go out and I see Snorkels.
但它在水里奇怪地扭着身体
But he's doing this weird twisting thing in the water.
苍天呐 天呐 天呐
Oh, god. Oh, god. Oh, god.
于是我划过去 发现有个塑料袋
So I paddle over, and I see he's got a plastic grocery bag,
将他的脖子和鳍勒在一起
wrapped around his neck and one of his fins.
我慌了 想方设法用船桨去帮他扯开
And I freaked, tried to get it off with my paddle.
但那不管用 于是我跳下水
It didn't work, so I-I jumped in,
可惜的是他已经沉入水中 之后
But he disappeared under the water. And, uh...
别说了 求你别说下去了
Don't say it. Don't you dare say it.
之后我就再也没见到他
And I never saw him again.
绝对是我听过的最悲伤的故事
This is the saddest thing I've ever--
米奇尔 你没事吧
Mitchell, are you okay?
怎么可能没事
Of course I'm not okay.
一切都那么糟糕郁闷
None of this is okay.
好吧 你得忍住了
Okay, well, you need to pull yourself together.
我们正在你老板家呢
'cause we're at your boss' house.
他淹死了 小卡
He drowned, Cam!
他没事吧
Is he all right?
没事 没事 我觉得他需要点新鲜空气
Yeah, yeah, I just think he needs a little air.
你知道谁还需要新鲜空气吗
You know who else needed air?
斯诺克斯
Snorkels!
抱歉
Excuse me.
斯诺克斯 你在哪里 斯诺克斯
Snorkels?! Where are you, Snorkels?!
米奇尔 快回来
Mitchell, get back here!
噢 斯诺克斯
Oh, Snorkels!
米奇尔 你这是怎么了
Mitchell, what is wrong with you?!
你以为我怎么了 我饿坏了
What do you think is wrong with me? I'm starving!
好吧 如果你饿了 就吃些东西吧
Well, if you're starving, then just eat something!
我不能吃东西 因为你会生我的气
I can't eat something because then you'll get mad at me,
而且我们现在在我老板家
And we're at my boss' house!
我不会生你的气
I'm not gonna get mad at you!
我很感谢你为我做的一切
I appreciate what you're doing for me!
我所做的一切也都是为了你
I'm doing it for you.
不 你不需要为我减肥
Oh, you don't have to do anything for me.
我就喜欢原原本本真实的你
I love you just the way you are.
我也喜欢原原本本真实的你
-我抓住你了 -好 好
- I got you! - Okay. Okay.
-我抓住你了 亲爱的 -谢谢
- I got you, babe! - Thank you.
我抓住你了
I got you!
-小卡 -我抓住你了
- Cam. - I got you!
脚能够到地 我自己站起来
I can walk. I can walk.
或许跟米奇尔只能做同事 无法做朋友
I think Mitchell may just be a work friend.
今天我让爸妈失望了 更糟糕的是
I let down my Mom and Dad today, and... Worse than that,
我也让老师失望了
I let down my teacher.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
跟我沾边的都得挨罚
Everything I touch turns to detention.
对不起 妈妈
I'm sorry, Mom.
我也是
Me, too.
算了吧 我今天也没法
Oh, I don't really have
站在什么道德高度上去说教你们了
a whole lot of moral high ground to stand on.
我自己也搞砸了
I wasn't exactly my best self today either.
总之 今天邓菲家族集体触霉头
All in all, not a great day for the Dunphys.
加油老爸 相信你自己
Come on, Dad! Believe in yourself!
你让一切不可能变得可能
You're making the impossible unimpossible.
菲尔 天呐
Phil. Oh, my god.
你省省吧 他正"闭关"练功呢
Don't even bother. He's in the zone.
他听不见你
He can't hear you.
加油 爸爸
Go, Dad!
你能行的
You got this!
一周来 我教育女儿都是在空口说白话
All week long, I'd been telling my girls how to act
而不是言传身教
instead of showing them.
但菲尔不是
But not Phil.
菲尔本可以说
Phil could have said,
艾丽克斯 放松点 别什么事都太较真
"Alex, relax. Don't take everything so seriously."
或者 海莉 尝试挑战 别轻易放弃
Or "Haley, challenge yourself. Don't give up so easily."
但菲尔没有选择言语教导 而是采取实际行动
But instead of talking the talk, Phil walked the walk.
这难道不正是我们应该
And isn't that what we're supposed to do
为所爱之人做的吗
for the people we love?
虽然是个挑战
It's definitely a challenge...
但菲尔让它看起来很简单
But Phil made it look easy,
七尺之上
7 feet off the ground.
你太棒了
You're awesome!
天呐 我做到了
Oh, my goodness!
原来 超级邓菲一直都在我身边
Turns out, I've had my super Dunphy all along.
我知道
Oh, I know.
我走钢丝的时候脑子里想着什么
What was on my mind as I was walking across that wire?
我一直在想 如果我能走钢丝
I kept thinking, if I can do this,
我就有两种方式穿过我家院子了
Then I've got two ways of getting across my yard.
你玩得高兴吗
Did you have fun?
嗯 她是世界上最可爱的狗狗
Yes. She's the cutest dog in the whole world.
够了 你第一次说的时候我就听见了
Yeah, I heard you the first time.
我们去找你爸爸们吧
Let's go find your Daddies.
我们在这儿呢
We're in here!
天呐 蛋糕真是太好吃了
Oh, my god. These cupcakes a so good.
抱歉 我们自己拿着吃了
I'm so sorry. We helped ourselves.
我们太饿了 这些蛋糕太美味了
We were so hungry. They are delicious.
话说我很喜欢甜而不腻的口味
I love that they're not too sweet, you know?
吃起来有点像小馅饼
They taste almost like pate.
我的意思是说
You know, I mean...
你们怎么吃东西了
But why are you eating?
我们之前在节食减肥呢
We've been on a juice cleanse.
你先自己一边儿玩去吧 亲爱的
You need to mind your own business, sweetie, for right now.